Guide to the Yale Summer and Special Programs Records Concerning the Summer Language Institute
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Summer and Special Programs records concerning the Summer Language Institute
1948-1979
RU 720
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
(6 boxes)
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, financial papers, applications, and fellowship materials of the Yale Summer and Special Programs documenting the operations and activities of the Summer Language Institute.
Yale Summer and Special Programs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 15-B (YRG 15-B) Records of specific summer and special programs
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details
Scope and Contents
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, financial papers, applications, and fellowship materials of the Yale Summer and Special Programs documenting the operations and activities of the Summer Language Institute
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession
Summer schools; Universities and colleges -- Administration; University extension; Yale Summer and Special Programs; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Summer Language Institute
- Records concerning the Summer Language Institute, 1948-1978; Accession 1983-A-044
  - Plans, general, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student list, 1948-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Russian, advanced, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Russian, elementary, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute for Far Eastern Languages Chinese, Japanese, French, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Russian: enrollment, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Plans and grades, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2024
  - Graduate French and German, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Eastern Languages: student list, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: staff, budget, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student and course list, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student lists, bursars list, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Language program
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Peace Corp, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Classrooms, building plans, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - National Defense Foreign Language Graduate Fellowships
    - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 1968 (lacking) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - 1970 (lacking) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - 1971 (lacking) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Faculty, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Restricted unti January 1, 2051
  - Statements
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 35 - 36)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Profiles, personnel, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Restricted until January 1, 2054
- Administrative records, 1976-1979; Accession 1983-A-117
  - Project budget, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Staff appointments and profiles, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Spring, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Fall, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Fall, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Spring, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Final grades (Box 1)
    Restricted until January 1, 2051